export const QuizData =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "Positive Attitude is ?",
            options: ['being happy' , 'develop a strong sense of balance' , 'avoid stress'],
            answer : 'develop a strong sense of balance'
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "Motivating people is ?",
            options: ['help others teammates' , 'go out with your teammates' , 'convince others about your ideas and work together'],
            answer : 'convince others about your ideas and work together'
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "A good leader needs ?",
            options: ['Discpline' , 'Money' , 'Work'],
            answer : 'Discpline'
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : "A strong leader include ?",
            options: ['negativity' , 'Patience' , 'ineffective feedback'],
            answer : 'Patience'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "A leader have to ?",
            options: ['Take risk' , 'do all the work' , 'give the work for teammates'],
            answer : 'Take risk'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "A good leader have to ?",
            options: ['Inspire others' , 'ignore others' , 'be kind'],
            answer : 'Inspire others'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "The best path to becoming a good leader is to always keep ?",
            options: ['working hard' , 'skiping others' , 'learning new things'],
            answer : 'learning new things'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "to build a strong team we need?",
            options: ['avoid leaders' , 'new leaders' , 'effective leaders'],
            answer : 'effective leaders'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : "One of the skills that differentiates leadership from many other competencies is ?",
            options: ['the ability to teach and mentor' , 'education' , 'the ability to talk to others'],
            answer : 'the ability to teach and mentor'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "Good leaders support ?",
            options: ['themselves' , 'stressful moment' , 'a positive environment'],
            answer : 'a positive environment'
        },



    ]

export const QC =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "Good communication skill can help you to  ?",
            options: ['understand others' , 'skip others' , 'win money'],
            answer : 'understand others'
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "Communication skill can ensure that you are able to ?",
            options: ['buy new product' , 'manage interactions with businesses and organisation', 'make a new friends'],
            answer : 'manage interactions with businesses and organisation'
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "Active listening means ?",
            options: ['talk with your teammates' , 'listen to music' , ' paying close attention to the person who is speaking to you'],
            answer : ' paying close attention to the person who is speaking to you'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "A key aspect of respect is knowing when to  ?",
            options: ['initiate communication and respond' , 'phone friends' , 'quit a discussion'],
            answer : 'initiate communication and respond'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "When there is a disagreement or conflict ?",
            options: ['be happy' , 'leave the discussion' , 'Be calm and consistent'],
            answer : 'Be calm and consistent'
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : "non-verbal communication is ?",
            options: ['body language' , 'paying attention' , 'skip others'],
            answer : 'body language'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "Good verbal communication means ?",
            options: ['talk to little' , 'talk to much' , 'saying just enough'],
            answer : 'saying just enough'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "Eye contact is ?",
            options: ['verbal communication' , 'non-verbal communication' , 'Active listening'],
            answer : 'non-verbal communication'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : "When you disagree with an employer , it is important to ?",
            options: ['respect their point of view' , 'quit the job' , 'dont talk to them another time '],
            answer : 'respect their point of view'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "A good communicator should enter into any conversation ?",
            options: ['at any time he want' , 'with a flexible, open mind' , 'with mistrust'],
            answer : 'with a flexible, open mind'
        },

    ]

export const QE =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "Personal Effectiveness refers to making  ?",
            options: ['the best use of your time' , 'others happy' , 'money'],
            answer : 'the best use of your time'
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "In order to achieve Personal Effectiveness we need to  ?",
            options: ['Work hard always' , 'Do all the work', 'Plan and organise your own work'],
            answer : 'Plan and organise your own work'
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "Our personal effectiveness depends on ?",
            options: ['the work experience' , 'the work we do' , 'the quantite of work'],
            answer : ' paying close attention to the person who is speaking to you'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "Our personal effectiveness depends also on  ?",
            options: ['our Ideas' , 'our Talents' , 'our Family'],
            answer : 'our Talents'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "Determination allows you to  ?",
            options: ['focus only on achieving a specific goal' , 'thinking to do all the job' , 'focus on achieving others goals'],
            answer : 'focus only on achieving a specific goal'
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : " Self-confidence is manifested in ?",
            options: ['conflict' , 'speech' , 'task'],
            answer : 'speech'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "Persistence makes you ?",
            options: ['keep moving forward regardless of emerging obstacles' , 'having many problemes in work ' , 'happy and in a good mood'],
            answer : 'keep moving forward regardless of emerging obstacles'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "Managing stress helps ?",
            options: ['skip stressful moments' , 'combat conflicts in daily live' , 'combat stress that arises in daily life'],
            answer : 'combat stress that arises in daily life'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : " Creativity requires ?",
            options: [' the ability to generate ideas' , 'using others ideas' , 'the ability to search for old ideas'],
            answer : ' the ability to generate ideas'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "An idea is ?",
            options: ['a goal to achieve' , 'a mental image of an object formed by the human mind' , 'a dream'],
            answer : 'a mental image of an object formed by the human mind'
        },

    ]

export const QP =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "If you want to build a legacy or leave a lasting impression on your customers you need ?",
            options: ['a good employees' , 'a good Appearance' , 'a good office'],
            answer : 'a good Appearance'
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "Demeanour means  ?",
            options: ['Be polite and well-spoken' , 'Be at time', 'Be a bad guy'],
            answer : 'Be polite and well-spoken'
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "When facing a difficult situation you have to  ?",
            options: ['Leave the job' , 'Maintain Your Poise' , 'Ask for help'],
            answer : 'Maintain Your Poise'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "Emotional Intelligence refers to how ?",
            options: ['we help others' , 'we love others' , 'we relate emotionally to people'],
            answer : 'we relate emotionally to people'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "Professionalism includes attributes as ?",
            options: ['Arriving on time to meetings' , 'Delaying meetings' , 'Be late on meetings'],
            answer : 'Arriving on time to meetings'
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : "Phone Etiquette means ?",
            options: ['having new phone' , 'talk always on phone' , 'identifying yourself by your full name'],
            answer : 'identifying yourself by your full name'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "Written Correspondence means ?",
            options: ['keep your letters brief and to the point' , 'write birthday letters ' , 'use any language in your letters'],
            answer : 'keep your letters brief and to the point'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "A professional can quickly and easily ?",
            options: ['make money' , 'find what is needed' , 'go home'],
            answer : 'find what is needed'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : "Negotiation is at the heart of ?",
            options: ['find new job' , 'buying with low price' , 'business deals'],
            answer : 'business deals'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "Negotiation requires ?",
            options: ['excellent communication' , 'talking to much' , 'having many friends'],
            answer : 'excellent communication'
        },

    ]

export const QM =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "Influencing Skills means ?",
            options: ['control people' , 'insist on my ideas' , 'get people to buy in to your goals'],
            answer : 'get people to buy in to your goals'
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "Organizing  means  ?",
            options: ['have a nice office' , 'creating structures to support or accomplish a plan ', 'be at time'],
            answer : 'creating structures to support or accomplish a plan '
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "The best managers are ?",
            options: ['good guys' , 'effective leaders' , 'always pissed off'],
            answer : 'effective leaders'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "Managers must know  ?",
            options: ['what is happening' , 'who work with them' , 'who came late at work'],
            answer : 'what is happening'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "Directing is the part where ?",
            options: ['you are the boss' , 'you take a nice office' , 'you take charge and delegate '],
            answer : 'you take charge and delegate '
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : "vital management skill is ?",
            options: ['helping others' , 'decision-making' , 'be ignoring'],
            answer : 'decision-making'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "Delegation helps the manager to ?",
            options: ['avoid wastage of time' , 'be happy' , 'stay home'],
            answer : 'avoid wastage of time'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "A good manager must have the ability to ?",
            options: ['solve the frequent problems' , 'search for new problems' , 'make problems'],
            answer : 'solve the frequent problems'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : "Good management skills are vital for  ?",
            options: ['any organization to have new employees' , 'any organization to make money quickly ' , 'any organization to succeed and achieve its goals and objectives'],
            answer : 'any organization to succeed and achieve its goals and objectives'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "Management skills used in  ?",
            options: ['making product' , 'decision-making' , 'problem-making'],
            answer : 'decision-making'
        },

    ]


export const QCA =
    [
        {
            id: 0 ,
            question : "Sustained Attention means ?",
            options: ['ability to look at, listen to and think about classroom tasks over a period of time' , 'ignore tasks out of time of work' , 'pay attention in work'],
            answer : 'ability to look at, listen to and think about classroom tasks over a period of time\''
        },
        {
            id: 1 ,
            question : "Speed of Information Processing refers to ?",
            options: ['number of information we learn on a day ' , 'how quickly a learner can process incoming information', 'how quickly an employees can do his work'],
            answer : 'how quickly a learner can process incoming information'
        },
        {
            id: 2 ,
            question : "Working Memory refers  ?",
            options: ['to the ability to remember instructions or keep information in the mind long enough to perform tasks' , 'to ability to remember  all the tasks' ],
            answer : 'to the ability to remember instructions or keep information in the mind long enough to perform tasks'
        },
        {
            id: 3 ,
            question : "ATTENTION/SUSTAINED  ?",
            options: ['Enables you to pay attention at who talk to you' , 'Enables you to pay attention at work for a sustained period of time' , ' Enables you to stay focused and on task for a sustained period of time'],
            answer : ' Enables you to stay focused and on task for a sustained period of time'
        },
        {
            id: 4 ,
            question : "ATTENTION/DIVIDED ?",
            options: ['Enables you to remember information while doing two things at once' , 'Enables you to remember who you meet today' , 'Enables you to remember all the information you learn '],
            answer : 'Enables you to remember information while doing two things at once'
        },
        {
            id: 5 ,
            question : "LOGIC & REASONING ?",
            options: ['Enables you to think quickly' , 'Enables you to reason, form ideas, and solve problems' , 'Enables you to quit when there is problems'],
            answer : 'Enables you to reason, form ideas, and solve problems'
        },
        {
            id: 6 ,
            question : "Cognitive abilities are ?",
            options: ['body skills' , 'brain-based skills' , 'hand skills'],
            answer : 'brain-based skills'
        },
        {
            id: 7 ,
            question : "Visual processing helps you effectively  ?",
            options: ['see others ideas' , 'read the thoughts of others' , 'interpret images'],
            answer : 'interpret images'
        },
        {
            id: 8 ,
            question : "you can improve your cognitive skills  ?",
            options: ['Exercise your brain' , 'Exercise your body ' , 'Exercise your hands'],
            answer : 'Exercise your brain'
        },
        {
            id: 9 ,
            question : "Each of your cognitive skills plays an important part in ?",
            options: ['making easily money' , 'having a new job' , 'processing new information '],
            answer : 'processing new information '
        },

    ]



